The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: Good morning everyone.
教授：大家早上好。
Morning.
早上。
Let's get started.
让我们开始吧。
So the second of two lectures on numerics.
因此，这是关于数值的两个讲座中的第二个。
Last time we had this motivating question
上次我们有这个激励性的问题
of finding the millionth digit of the square root of 2,
找到2的平方根的百万分之一
or the square root of quantities that
或数量的平方根
end up becoming irrational.
最终变得不理性。
And we talked about high-precision arithmetic,
我们谈到了高精度算术，
and we use Newton's method to compute the square roots.
我们使用牛顿法计算平方根。
You saw a demo of computing square roots,
您看到了一个计算平方根的演示，
but there's a few things missing.
但还有一些遗漏的地方。
We don't quite know how to do division, which
我们不太清楚如何进行除法
is required for the Newton's method,
是牛顿法所必需的
and we didn't really talk at all about algorithmic complexity
而且我们根本没有谈论算法复杂性
beyond talking about the complexity of multiplication.
除了谈论乘法的复杂性。
So multiplication is a primitive that at this point
所以乘法是一个原始的东西
we know how to do in a couple of different ways,
我们知道如何通过几种不同的方式
including the naive order n squared
包括天真阶n平方
algorithm and the Karatsuba algorithm,
算法和唐津算法，
which is something like n raised to 1.58.
就像n升到1.58一样。
But how many times is multiplication
但是乘法是多少次
called when you compute square roots?
计算平方根时调用？
In fact, multiplication is called
实际上，乘法称为
when you call the division operator
当您致电除法运算符
when you compute square roots.
当计算平方根时。
So there's really two levels off a computation going on here
所以计算实际上有两个层次
and we need to open this up, and look at in detail,
我们需要打开它，并仔细研究，
and figure out what our overall algorithmic complexity is.
并弄清楚我们整体的算法复杂度是多少。
So that's really the meat of today's lecture.
所以这确实是今天演讲的内容。
Getting to the point where we know
到达我们知道的地步
what we have with respect to asymptotic complexity
关于渐进复杂性我们有什么
of computing the square root of a number.
计算一个数字的平方根。
So let me start with a review of what we covered last time.
因此，让我开始回顾上一次讨论的内容。
We decided that we wanted the millionth digit
我们决定想要百万位数字
of square root of 2.
2的平方根
And the way we're going to do this
而我们要做的方式
is by working with integers and computing the floor,
是通过使用整数并计算下限，
since we needed to be an integer, of 2 times 10 raised
因为我们需要是一个整数，所以要加2乘以10
to 2d, where d is the number of digits of precision.
到2d，其中d是精度的位数。
N over there.
N那边。
So we'll take a look at an example or two
所以我们来看一个或两个例子
here as to how this works with integers.
这里是关于整数如何工作的。
But what we do is compute essentially the floor
但是我们要做的是本质上计算下限
of some quantity a, the square root of some quantity a,
一定数量a的平方根
via Newton's method.
通过牛顿的方法。
And the way Newton's method works
牛顿方法的工作方式
is you go through an iteration.
您是否经历了迭代。
You start with x0 being one, which is your initial guess,
您以x0为1开始，这是您最初的猜测，
and compute xi plus 1 equals xi plus a divided by xi over 2.
并计算xi加1等于xi加除以xi得出2。
And as you can see, this requires division,
如您所见，这需要划分，
because we're computing a divided by xi.
因为我们正在计算除以xi。
That's the outer Newton iteration.
那是外部的牛顿迭代。
And I said a couple of things that's said
我说了几句话
you are going to have a quadratic rate of convergence.
您将具有二次收敛速度。
The precision with respect to the number of digits
关于位数的精度
is going to increase by a factor of 2 every iteration.
每次迭代将增加2倍。
And so if you started out with one digit of precision,
因此，如果您以一位精度开始，
you go to two, then four, eight, et cetera.
你去两个，然后四个，八个，等等。
And so that's a geometric progression.
这是一个几何级数。
And that means that we're going to have
这意味着我们将拥有
a logarithmic number of iterations, which is nice.
对数的迭代次数，这很好。
And we were all happy about that, and you believed me.
我们对此都很高兴，您相信我。
I gave you an example and it looked pretty good,
我举了一个例子，看起来不错，
but didn't really prove anything about the rate of convergence.
但并未真正证明收敛速度。
What I'd like to do now is take a look at this particular
我现在想做的就是看一下这个特殊的
iterative computation, where we're computing xi plus 1 given
迭代计算，我们计算xi加1
xi , and argue that this, in fact,
xi并认为实际上
has a quadratic rate of convergence.
具有二次收敛速度。
So you can think of this as doing
所以你可以认为这是在做
an error analysis of Newton's method.
牛顿法的误差分析。
And let's say that xn equals square root of a 1 plus epsilon
假设xn等于1加epsilon的平方根
n, where epsilon may be positive or negative.
n，其中ε可以为正或负。
So we have an error associated with xn
所以我们有一个与xn相关的错误
in the n-th iteration with respect to what we want,
关于我们想要的，在第n次迭代中，
which is the square root of a.
这是a的平方根。
And it's off by something.
它因某种原因而关闭。
It may be a large quantity in the beginning.
一开始可能数量很大。
We want to show convergence, so obviously we
我们想展示融合，所以显然
want epsilon n, as n becomes large, do tend to 0.
想要εn，随着n变大，确实趋于0。
How fast does this approach 0?
该方法接近0的速度如何？
That's the question.
这就是问题所在。
And so if you take this equation and plug this into that,
因此，如果您采用这个方程式并将其插入其中，
and say, what is xn plus 1?
并说xn加1是多少？
xn plus 1 would be square root of a times 1 plus epsilon n
xn加1将乘以1加epsilon n的平方根
plus a divided by square root of a 1 plus epsilon
加上1加epsilon的平方根除
n divided by 2.
n除以2。
Just plugging it in, the value of xn.
只需插入xn的值即可。
And then some a couple of steps of algebraic simplification,
然后进行几步代数简化，
you can pull out the square root of a here,
您可以在此处拉出a的平方根，
then you have 1 plus epsilon n, 1
那么你有1加epsilon n，1
divided by 1 plus epsilon n over here.
在此除以1加epsilon n。
The whole thing divided by 2.
整个事情除以2。
And if you keep going-- there's one step that I'm skipping here
如果您继续前进-我在这里跳过了一步
in terms of simplification, but let
在简化方面，但让
me write this last result out.
我把最后的结果写出来。
Which is xn plus 1 is square root of a times 1
xn加1是乘以1的平方根
plus epsilon n squared divided by 2 times 1
加epsilon n平方除以2 1
plus epsilon n down at the bottom.
在底部加上epsilon n。
So what do we have here in terms of the overall observation
那么，我们在整体观察方面有什么
for epsilon n plus 1, which is the error in the n
对于epsilon n加1，这是n中的误差
plus 1-th iteration given that you have an epsilon n
假设您有一个epsilon n，再加上第1次迭代
error in the n-th iteration?
在第n次迭代中出错？
You have a relationship like so where epsilon n plus 1
你有这样的关系，其中εn加1
is related to epsilon n whole square.
与epsilon n整个平方有关。
And this part here, as n becomes large,
随着n变大，
epsilon n is going to go to 0 assuming
epsilon n假设为0
a decent initial guess.
不错的初步猜测。
And so you can say that this is essentially
所以你可以说这本质上是
1, which means you have this quadratic rate of convergence
1，表示您具有这种二次收敛速度
where the error, which is a small quantity,
误差很小的地方
is getting squared at every iteration.
每次迭代都会平方。
And so if you have something like a 0.01 error
因此，如果您遇到0.01错误
at the beginning for epsilon n, epsilon n squared
在epsilon n的开头，epsilon n平方
is going to be 0.0001.
将是0.0001。
So that's where you get the quadratic rate of convergence.
这样便可以得到二次收敛率。
So it really comes from this relationship, the relationship
所以它真的来自这种关系
epsilon n squared to epsilon n plus 1,
epsilon n等于epsilon n加1
Any questions about this?
对此有任何疑问吗？
Great.
大。
So if you have the quadratic rate of convergence,
因此，如果您具有二次收敛速度，
if you want to go to d digits of precision like I have here,
如果您想像我在这里一样达到d位精度，
you can argue that you need to log d iterations.
您可以辩称您需要记录d次迭代。
So that's kind of nice, you have a logarithmic number
很好，您有一个对数
of iterations.
的迭代。
I'm going to get back to that.
我将回到这一点。
There's one little subtlety that is associated
有一点点微妙之处
with asymptotic analysis that goes beyond simply
渐进分析不仅限于此
the number of iterations that you have
您拥有的迭代次数
and the digits of precision.
和精度的数字。
But so far so good.
但是到目前为止还不错。
We're happy with this logarithmic number
我们对这个对数感到满意
of iterations.
的迭代。
And if we can now compute the complexity of the division,
如果现在我们可以计算除法的复杂度，
then obviously we need an algorithm for that.
那么显然我们需要一种算法。
But if you have an algorithm and we figure out
但是，如果您有一个算法，我们会找出
what the complexity of the division algorithm is,
除法算法的复杂度是多少，
then we have complexity for the square root of 2
那么我们有2的平方根的复杂度
or square root of a using Newton's method.
或使用牛顿法的平方根。
So just justified what I said last time with respect
所以有理由说我上次所说的尊重
to quadratic rate of convergence.
到二次收敛速度。
And then we talked about multiplication last time.
然后我们上次谈到乘法。
I want to revisit that.
我想重温一下。
You have multiplication algorithms,
你有乘法算法，
and we want to be able to multiply d digit numbers.
并且我们希望能够将d位数字相乘。
And the naive algorithm.
和朴素的算法。
And you could imagine doing divide and conquer.
您可以想象分而治之。
So you take x1, x0; y1, y0 where x1
所以你取x1，x0; y1，y0其中x1
is the most significant half of x.
是x的最高有效部分。
You're trying to multiply x times y.
您正在尝试将x乘以y。
And same thing for y1 and y0.
对于y1和y0同样如此。
So each of these will have d by 2, digits of precision.
因此，每一个的d精度为2位。
And if you implement the naive algorithm that
如果您实施了朴素的算法，
looks like tn equals 4 tn by 2 plus theta n,
看起来tn等于4 tn乘2加then n，
you end up with theta n squared complexity out
你最终得到的是复杂度的平方
so you have to do four multiplications corresponding
所以你必须做四个乘法
to x1 times Y1 x1 times y0, et cetera.
x1乘以Y1 x1乘以y0，等等。
And at each level in the recursive tree,
在递归树的每个级别上
you're breaking things down by a factor of 2 respect
你把事情分解成2个方面
to the digits of precision that you
达到您的精确度
need to multiply on as you're going down the tree.
当你要往树下走时，需要乘以。
And this is the four multiplications.
这是四个乘法。
You get your theta n squared complexity.
您可以得到复杂度的平方。
This gentleman by the name of Karatsuba
这位以唐津为名的绅士
recognized that you could play a few mathematical tricks, which
认识到您可以玩一些数学技巧，
I won't go over again, but reduce
我不会再走了，但要减少
to three multiplications.
到三个乘法。
And you do a few more additions, but given
然后再添加一些，
that the additions have theta n complexity,
这些添加物具有复杂性，
the recurrence relationship turns into tn equals 3t of n
递归关系变成tn等于n的3t
over 2 plus theta n.
超过2加theta n。
And this ends up having 1.58 dot dot dot complexity.
这样最终将具有1.58点点点复杂度。
No reason to stop with breaking things up into two parts.
没有理由停止将事情分解为两个部分。
You could imagine generalizing Karatsuba
您可以想象一下唐津
and people have done this.
人们已经做到了。
Two different researchers, Toom and Cook,
两位不同的研究人员Toom和Cook
generalized Karatsuba for the case
案件的广义唐津
where k is greater than or equal to 2, where
其中k大于或等于2，其中
you're breaking it into k parts.
您将其分为k个部分。
So the Toom-Cook 2 algorithm is basically Karatsuba,
所以Toom-Cook 2算法基本上是Karatsuba，
but you have Toom 3, Toom 4, and so on.
但您有Toom 3，Toom 4等。
And I'm not going to give you a lot of details on this.
我不会在此提供很多细节。
We don't expect you to work on this, at least in 6006.
我们不希望您至少在6006上进行此工作。
But just to give you a sense of what happens,
但是只是为了让您了解发生了什么，
the Toom 3 method, or the Toom-Cook 3 method,
Toom 3方法或Toom-Cook 3方法，
breaks and number up into three parts.
分为三个部分。
So each of these would have d by 3 digits of precision.
因此，每个精度将具有3位数的d精度。
So this is what you're starting out with.
这就是您要开始的。
You're starting out with a d digit number.
您将从广告数字开始。
But the very first level of recursion, you're
但是第一级递归
going to break things up into three xi numbers that
要将事情分解成三个xi数
are d by 3 digits long.
d长3位数。
Same thing for y.
y也一样。
And if you did a naive multiplication of this,
如果您对此进行了幼稚的乘法，
how many multiplications do I need?
我需要多少个乘法？
If I just forget about any mathematical tricks,
如果我忘了任何数学技巧，
if I just tried to multiply these things out,
如果我只是想把这些东西加倍，
how many d by 3 by d by 3 multiplications do I need?
我需要几乘三乘三乘？
AUDIENCE: Nine.
听众：九。
PROFESSOR: Nine.
教授：九岁。
So if you can beat nine using mathematical tricks,
因此，如果您可以使用数学技巧击败九个，
you have a better divide and conquer algorithm.
您有更好的分而治之算法。
And it turns out that Toom 3 plays some arithmetic games
事实证明，《毁灭战士3》玩了一些算术游戏
and ends up with a recurrence relationship that
并以递归关系结束
looks like this.
看起来像这样。
Where you reduce the nine multiplications down to five.
将九个乘法减为五个。
So that's a win.
所以这是一个胜利。
And that ends up being theta of n raised to what?
最终将n的theta提升到什么？
Someone?
有人吗
Someone loudly.
有人大声。
Log--
日志-
AUDIENCE: Base 3.
观众：基础3。
PROFESSOR: Log with a base 3 of 5.
教授：以5为底的3进行登录。
Another irrational number.
另一个不合理的数字。
And this ends up being n raised to 1.465.
最终将n提升到1.465。
So you won.
所以你赢了。
If you use Toom 3, assuming the constants worked out--
如果您使用的是Toom 3，请假设常量已经计算出-
and Victor can say a little bit more
维克多可以多说一点
about that, because we're having a little trouble justifying
关于这一点，因为我们在论证方面有些麻烦
this particular problem set question
这个特定的问题集问题
that we want to give you, given the constant factors involved.
考虑到所涉及的恒定因素，我们希望给您。
So the issue really here is this is correct.
因此，这里的问题确实是正确的。
It's n raised to 1.46.
升至1.46。
That's n raised to 1.5.
那是n提高到1.5。
And then the naive algorithm is n square.
那么朴素的算法是n平方。
But how big does n have to be in order
但是n必须有多大才能排列
for the n raised to 1.58 algorithm
用于将n提升至1.58算法
to beat the n square algorithm, and for the n raised
击败n方算法，并提出n
to 1.46 algorithm to beat the n raised
以1.46算法击败n提出
to 1.58 algorithm, et cetera.
到1.58算法等。
And it turns out n needs to be really, really large
事实证明，n必须非常大
if you implement these in Python.
如果您在Python中实现这些功能。
So if you're having a little trouble here,
因此，如果您在这里遇到一些麻烦，
giving you this pristine problem set
给你这个原始的问题集
that you can go off and learn about multiplication,
您可以开始学习乘法，
and also appreciate asymptotic complexity.
并且欣赏渐近复杂性。
So that's a bit of a catch-22.
因此，这有点让人难以接受。
Anyway, for the purposes of theory, this is great.
无论如何，就理论而言，这是伟大的。
It turns people have done even better.
事实证明，人们做得更好。
Multiplication is just this obviously incredibly important
乘法显然很重要
primitive that you would need for doing
您需要做的原始
any reasonable computation.
任何合理的计算。
And so people have worked on using things like fast Fourier
因此人们努力使用快速傅立叶
transforms and other techniques improve
转换和其他技术改进
the complexity of multiplication.
乘法的复杂性。
And best scheme until a few years
最好的方案，直到几年
ago was this scheme called Schonhage-Strassen scheme,
这个方案以前叫做Schonhage-Strassen方案，
which is almost linear in complexity.
复杂度几乎是线性的。
It's n log n log log n time.
这是n log n log log n时间。
And this uses the fast Fourier transform, FFT.
这使用了快速傅立叶变换FFT。
And you can play with all of these things.
您可以玩所有这些东西。
You can play with Karatsuba the naive algorithm, Toom 3,
您可以使用Karatsuba玩天真算法Toom 3，
et cetera in the gmpy package in Python.
等在Python的gmpy包中。
And you can see as to what the value of n
你可以看到n的值是多少
needs to be in order for one of these algorithms
需要是为了这些算法之一
to beat the other.
击败对方。
This is not something that you're
这不是你
going to do specifically in the problem set,
要专门针对问题集
but I say that as an aside.
但我要说的是
These algorithms are implemented,
这些算法已实现，
and they're used in real life.
它们被用于现实生活中。
Eric?
埃里克？
ERIC: It may be worth mentioning that Python itself
ERIC：也许值得一提的是Python本身
for long integers uses Karatsuba.
对于长整数，请使用Karatsuba。
PROFESSOR: Yeah, so Python uses-- beyond a certain n,
教授：是的，所以Python使用了-超过了n
you are going to have decisions that
你将要做出决定
are made within the package.
在包装内制成。
And Python shifts to Karatsuba after n becomes large.
n变大后，Python移至唐津。
But if n is small, then it's going
但是如果n小，那将会
to run the naive algorithm.
运行天真的算法。
Now if you write your own multiplication,
现在，如果您编写自己的乘法，
you can do whatever you want.
你想做什么，就可以做什么。
You can have your own adaptive scheme, assuming you
您可以拥有自己的自适应方案，前提是您
have many of these algorithms implemented,
实施了许多这样的算法，
or you're calling them using the gmpy package.
或者您使用gmpy软件包致电给他们。
So lastly, this looked pretty good for a while.
所以最后，这看起来好一阵子了。
And from a theoretical standpoint
从理论上讲
there was a breakthrough.
有一个突破。
Guy by the name of Furer came up with this algorithm that
名为Furer的Guy提出了这种算法
is n log n-- and let me write this carefully-- 2 raised
是n log n--让我仔细写下这个-提出2
big O-- that's an upper bound-- of log star n.
对数星n的大O值（即上限）。
That makes sense?
那讲得通？
No.
没有。
I'll have to explain it.
我必须解释一下。
OK, so what does this mean?
好，那是什么意思？
This part is clear.
这部分很清楚。
This is like sorting.
这就像排序。
It doesn't need to really use sorting, but that's n log n.
它并不需要真正使用排序，但这是n log n。
And then you have this 2 raised to big O log star n.
然后，您将这2个星提升为大对数星n。
I need to define what log star n is.
我需要定义什么是对数星n。
And log star n is what's called the iterative algorithm--
对数星号n是所谓的迭代算法-
logarithm, rather.
对数，而不是。
I guess it's an iterative algorithm,
我想这是一个迭代算法，
but it computes logs.
但它会计算日志。
And the iterative logarithm is the number
迭代对数是数字
of times log needs to be applied to get a result that
次数需要应用日志以获得结果
is less than or equal to 1.
小于或等于1。
So this thing really cuts you down to size really fast.
因此，这件事确实可以迅速缩小您的尺寸。
So it doesn't matter.
所以没关系。
You could be a 10 raised to 24, or 2 raised to 50,
您可以将10提高到24，或将2提高到50，
let's say, if you were doing binary logs.
假设您正在执行二进制日志。
And in the very first iteration you go down to 50, right?
在第一次迭代中，您降低到50，对吗？
And then you take a log of 50 and you go down to about 7
然后取对数50，然后下降到大约7
or something.
或者其他的东西。
And then you take the log of 7.
然后取7的对数。
And if you're talking about base 2, like we were,
而且，如果您像我们一样在谈论基地2，
you're down to less than 3.
您不到3岁。
And so four or five iterations, you're
所以四到五次迭代，
down to less than or equal to 1.
小于或等于1。
And that's what log star n computes.
这就是对数星n的计算结果。
It's not the logarithm as much as the number of times
对数不如次数多
so you have to apply log to get the result that's less than
因此，您必须应用日志才能获得小于
or equal to 1.
或等于1。
So you have these giant numbers, and it's only like five,
所以你有这些巨大的数字，只有五个，
six, eight times do you apply log and you're down to one.
六，八次您应用日志，而您将日志减少到一。
So for all practical purposes, you can think of--
因此，出于所有实际目的，您可以想到-
and this is upper bound-- you can think of this,
这是上限-您可以想到这一点，
even though this is 2 raised to something,
即使这个数字是2
it's 2 raised to a pretty small number.
它的2被提高到很小的数目。
2 raised to 10, that would be 1,000.
2提高到10，即为1,000。
And so from an asymptotic complexity standpoint,
因此，从渐近复杂度的角度来看，
this is the winner.
这是赢家。
From a practical standpoint, Schonhage-Strassen
从实际的角度来看，Schonhage-Strassen
is really what you probably want to use
确实是您可能想要使用的
when n becomes very large, to the billions
当n变得非常大时，达到数十亿
and so on and so forth.
等等等等。
And as of now, to the best of my knowledge
到目前为止，据我所知
this hasn't been implemented in the gmpy package.
gmpy包中尚未实现此功能。
So if you actually want to use gmpy, this is where you stop.
因此，如果您实际上想使用gmpy，那么这里就是您要停止的地方。
So that's multiplication.
这就是乘法。
So we have a bunch of different ways
所以我们有很多不同的方式
that you could do multiplication.
你可以做乘法。
What I'd like to do is give you a sense of assuming a given
我想做的是给您一种假设的感觉
complexity of multiplication, how long would division take?
乘法的复杂性，除法需要多长时间？
So we are 1 and 1/2 lectures in, and I haven't really
所以我们有1和1/2讲课，我还没有
told you how we're going to do division, which
告诉你我们要怎么做除法
is what we have to do when we compute a divided by xi, which
是我们计算除以xi时要做的
is the basic integration in the Newton method.
是牛顿法的基本积分。
So let's get to that.
因此，让我们开始吧。
So finally high-precision division.
于是终于进行了高精度分割。
So we want a high-precision rep off a divided by b.
因此，我们希望得到由a除以b的高精度rep。
And we're going to compute a high-precision rep
我们将计算一个高精度的rep
off 1 divided by b first.
先将1除以b。
And what we mean by that is that we'll
我们的意思是，我们将
compute r divided by b floor where
计算r除以b楼，其中
r is a really large value.
r是一个非常大的值。
And more importantly, it's easy to divide
更重要的是，划分很容易
by r in a particular base.
由r在特定基数中得出。
So for example, r equals 2 raised to k,
因此，例如，r等于2升为k，
when we use base 2, you can easily
当我们使用基数2时，您可以轻松
divide through a shift operator.
除以移位运算符。
So if I give you r divided by b and I give you
所以如果我给你r除以b然后我给你
this long computer word that's in base 2, which typically
以2为基数的较长计算机字词，通常
could have millions of digits in its representation,
表示中可能有数百万个数字，
I can shift that by the appropriate amount
我可以把它调适量
to a given r divided by b.
给定的r除以b。
I can get 1 over b by shifting that quantity.
通过移动该数量，我可以获得b的1分。
So it feels like, hey wait a minute.
感觉就像，嘿，等等。
Why are we dividing by r?
为什么我们要除以r？
Well remember that you want 1 over b.
好吧，请记住，您想要1比b。
And if you're computing r divided by b floor,
如果您要计算r除以b楼，
and you actually want 1 over b, which then you
而您实际上想要1比b大，那么您
could use to multiply by a so you can run your Newton
可以用来乘以a，这样就可以运行牛顿
iteration, then you want to divide by r.
迭代，那么您想除以r。
And that division is essentially going
这种分裂本质上正在发展
to be something that shifts things to the right.
成为使事物向右移动的事物。
So the most significant bits move to the right,
因此，最高有效位向右移动，
and you get a smaller number.
你得到一个较小的数字。
That make sense?
有道理？
So we all know how to divide by using
所以我们都知道如何使用
shifting assuming the bases work out right.
假设基数正确，则进行移位。
And if you had a representation that was decimal,
如果您使用的是十进制表示，
suddenly you could certainly divide by 10 raised to k.
突然之间，您当然可以除以10升至k。
That's easy.
这很容易。
You've done this many times.
您已经做了很多次。
But you just changed the decimal point
但是你改变了小数点
when you're working with decimal arithmetic.
当您使用十进制算术时。
When you divide 72 by 100 and you get 0.72.
将72除以100得到0.72。
And that's a very similar notion here.
这是一个非常相似的概念。
It doesn't really matter what base you're talking about.
您在说什么基础都没有关系。
So that's the setup.
这就是设置。
That's how are we going to try and tackle
那就是我们要尝试解决的方式
this division problem.
这个分裂问题。
But we still have this problem of computing r divided by b.
但是我们仍然存在计算r除以b的问题。
So how are we going to compute r divided by b?
那么我们如何计算r除以b？
And we want this to be a large number of digits of precision.
我们希望这是大量的精度数字。
So we're going to use Newton's method again.
因此，我们将再次使用牛顿方法。
You've got some non-linearity here with respect to 1 over x.
关于x上的1，这里有一些非线性。
And we're gonna use Newton's method again.
我们将再次使用牛顿方法。
And we'll have to hope that this works out,
我们必须希望这能解决，
that we can get Newton's method, it'll converge,
我们可以得到牛顿法，它将收敛，
and it'll require operations that we know how to do.
并且需要我们知道该怎么做的操作。
And all of this is going to work out really well.
所有这些都将很好地解决。
I'm going to set up a function, f
我要设置一个功能，f
of x equals 1 divided by x minus b divided by r.
x等于1除以x减去b除以r。
So what this means is that this function has
所以这意味着这个功能有
a 0 at x equals r divided by b.
x处的a 0等于r除以b。
So if I try and find the 0 of this function,
因此，如果我尝试找到此函数的0，
and I start out with a decent initial guess,
我从一个不错的初步猜测开始
I'm going to end up with r divided by b.
我将最终得到r除以b。
And if I'm working with integers,
如果我使用整数，
effectively that's the floor that I have for r divided by b.
实际上，这是我对r的下限除以b。
And then I do my shift and I end up with 1 over b.
然后我做我的班次，最终得到1分。
So someone who remembers differentiation,
所以有人记得差异化
if you're gonna apply Newton's method,
如果您要应用牛顿法，
tell me what the derivative of f of x is.
告诉我x的f的导数是什么。
Somebody's stretching at the back,
有人在后面伸展
but I don't think that was an answer.
但我不认为这是答案。
Someone at the back?
有人在后面吗？
Too easy a question?
问题太简单了吗？
For the cushion.
为垫子。
AUDIENCE: 1 over negative x squared.
观众：负数x平方的1。
PROFESSOR: 1 over negative x squared.
教授：负1的x平方。
Who's that?
那是谁？
All right.
好吧。
You can come pick this up.
你可以来接。
Whatever.
随你。
Cut the monotony here.
在这里剪切单调。
Just veered to the left.
刚刚转向左侧。
I think next time I'm going to weight them or something.
我想下一次我要对它们进行加权。
Let's just do frisbees next time.
下次再玩飞盘吧。
It makes it easy.
这很容易。
Forget cushions.
忘了坐垫。
No?
没有？
Frisbees or cushions?
飞盘还是坐垫？
How many want frisbees?
有多少想要飞盘？
How many want cushions?
有多少人想要坐垫？
Frisbees win.
飞盘获胜。
So you got derivative of x is minus 1 divided by x squared.
因此，您得到x的导数为负1除以x的平方。
And then if you go off and apply Newton's method--
然后，如果您开始采用牛顿方法-
and I'm not going to go through the symbolic equations here
而且我不会在这里讨论符号方程式
associated with Newton's method--
与牛顿法有关的-
but that's basically the same as we did before.
但这基本上与我们之前相同。
You are computing a tangent, and the new value of xi plus 1
您正在计算切线，并且xi的新值加1
given the value of xi is the x-intercept.
给定xi的值是x截距。
And we needed the derivative to compute that.
我们需要导数来计算。
But bottom line, you have xi plus 1 equals
但底线是xi加1等于
xi minus f of xi divided by f prime of xi.
xi减去xi的f除以xi的f素数。
So that's the Newton iteration.
这就是牛顿迭代。
And it's worth plugging in the various values here.
在这里插入各种值是值得的。
1 divided by xi minus b divided by r.
1除以xi减去b除以r。
That's f of x on top divided by minus 1 divided by xi square.
就是顶部的x的f除以负1除以xi平方。
So that's the derivative over here.
这就是这里的派生词。
So all I'm doing is plugging things in.
所以我要做的就是插上东西。
But you want to visualize this because this is really
但是您想将其形象化，因为这确实
what we need to compute.
我们需要计算什么。
And we have xi plus 1 equals xi plus xi square times
我们有xi加1等于xi加xi平方乘
1 over xi minus b divided by r.
xi减去b乘以r得到1。
And finally I get 2xi minus b xi square divided by r.
最后我得到2xi减去b xi平方除以r。
That is key.
那是关键。
This is pretty important.
这很重要。
So let's us look all the way to the left, which
因此，让我们一直向左看
is xi plus 1, all the way to the right, 2 times xi.
是xi加1，一直到右边，是xi的2倍。
That doesn't scare us, 2 times something.
这并不吓我们，两倍。
Especially base 2, pretty easy.
尤其是基数2，非常容易。
That's a multiply.
那是一个乘数。
Multiplies don't scare us because we
乘法不会吓我们，因为我们
know how to do multiplies anyway.
知道如何做乘法。
This is a simple multiply.
这是一个简单的乘法。
And then I got a square here.
然后我在这里有了一个正方形。
Square.
广场。
Not a square root.
不是平方根。
Squares don't scare us because that's a multiply,
正方形不会吓到我们，因为那是乘积，
just multiplying the same number to itself.
只是将相同的数字相乘。
And this doesn't scare us because we
这并不吓我们，因为我们
know that we've chosen r to be an easy division.
知道我们已经选择r为简单除法。
So all of the operations here are either easy,
因此，这里的所有操作都很简单，
or they require a multiply.
或它们需要相乘。
So remember I'm going to put a picture up towards the end here
所以请记住，我要在这里画一张画
that tells you the overall structure for computing
告诉您计算的整体结构
square root of a or square root of 2.
的平方根或2的平方根
But we've just sort of sold out to Newton, if you will.
但是，如果您愿意的话，我们有点卖完了。
Because we said that we're going to use Newton's method
因为我们说过要使用牛顿法
to compute essentially, iteratively, square root of a.
基本上迭代地计算a的平方根。
And within the Newton method, the first iteration,
在牛顿法中，第一次迭代
if you will, of the Newton method,
如果可以的话，用牛顿法
we had to compute a reciprocal.
我们必须计算一个倒数。
We had to compute 1 over xi.
我们必须在xi上计算1。
And in order to compute 1 over xi,
为了在xi上计算1
we're going to apply Newton's method again like I showed over
我将再次展示牛顿方法
here and over there.
在这里和那里。
And so that division is going to require iteration.
因此，该划分将需要迭代。
But the iteration at the second level is one of multiplication.
但是第二级的迭代是乘法之一。
You're gonna repeatedly apply multiplication
您将反复应用乘法
because you're going to go xi plus 1
因为你要去xi加1
based on xi using multiplication and some easy operations.
基于xi的乘法和一些简单的运算。
And then you go xi plus 2, xi plus 3, and so on and so forth.
然后转到xi加2，xi加3，依此类推。
That make sense?
有道理？
I'll try and put this up to give you the complete picture
我会尽力把它给你完整的图片
once we're done talking about the division
一旦我们完成了关于部门的讨论
algorithm and its complexity.
算法及其复杂性。
But before I do that, I just want
但是在我这样做之前，我只想
to give you a sense of the convergence of this scheme.
让您对该方案的融合有所了解。
Again, I want to give you an example first,
同样，我想先给你一个例子，
and then I'll argue about the convergence.
然后我将讨论融合问题。
You have to run this iteratively.
您必须迭代地运行它。
You've got to make i to get to the point
你必须让我明白这一点
where it's large enough that you have your digits of precision.
足够大的地方，您就可以拥有足够的精度。
And just as an example, let's say
举个例子，
we want r divided by b equals 2 raised to 16 divided by 5.
我们希望r除以b等于2升为16除以5。
So this is a fairly straightforward example.
因此，这是一个非常简单的示例。
But when you get up to integers, it turns out it's evocative.
但是当您使用整数时，事实证明它令人回味。
So r was selected to be 2 raised to k to make for easy division.
因此，r被选择为2升至k以便于除法。
And what I really want is that.
我真正想要的是那个。
And I want to see how I get to that using Newton's method.
我想看看如何使用牛顿方法实现这一目标。
And our initial guess, let's say we
我们最初的猜测，假设我们
try 2 raised to 16 divided by 4, because we
尝试将2提高到16除以4，因为我们
know how to divide by a power of two.
知道如何除以二的幂。
And so that's 2 raised to 14.
所以将2提高到14
And that's our initial guess.
这是我们最初的猜测。
So think of that as being x0.
因此，将其视为x0。
That is x0.
那就是x0。
And that 16384.
然后是16384。
x1 is going to be 2 times 16384, which is exactly that,
x1将是16384的2倍，就是这样
minus 5 times 16384 whole square.
负5倍16384全平方。
So now you're starting to square a fairly big number.
因此，现在您开始对相当大的数字求平方。
And obviously if you'd started with an even bigger r,
很明显，如果您从更大的r开始，
this would be a large number.
这将是一个很大的数目。
You go 65536 equals-- and this is 12288.
你去65536等于-这是12288。
So you really have one digit of precision there.
因此，您在那里确实有一位精度。
But the next time around, you get 2 times 12288 minus 5
但是下一次，您将获得2倍12288减5
times 12288 square divided by 65536.
12288平方除以65536。
And this division is easy.
而且这种划分很容易。
It's a shift.
这是一个转变。
You get to 13056.
您到达13056。
And I won't write this whole thing out,
而且我不会把整个事情写出来，
but if you take that, the next thing you'll get is 13107.
但是如果您采取了这种措施，那么接下来您会得到13107。
So as you can see, there's rapid convergence here.
如您所见，这里有快速的融合。
And you can actually do a very similar analysis to the epsilon
实际上，您可以进行与epsilon非常相似的分析
analysis-- and I'll put it in the notes,
分析-我将其放在笔记中，
but I won't do it here-- that I did for the square root
但我不会在这里做-我是为平方根做的
iteration to show that you have a quadratic the rate
迭代以显示速率为平方
of convergence when you apply Newton's method to division as
将牛顿方法应用于除法时的收敛性
well.
好。
So you can prove that using the symbolic analysis than we
因此，您可以证明，使用符号分析比我们
did very similar to the epsilon n relationship
与epsilon n关系非常相似
to epsilon n plus 1.
到epsilon n plus 1。
I'd suggest that it's a difference equation
我建议这是一个差分方程
here so that analysis is not exactly the same.
这里的分析并不完全相同。
But you can run through that, and you
但是你可以解决这个问题
can read that in the notes.
可以在笔记中阅读。
So we're in business.
所以我们做生意。
Finally things are looking up with respect
终于，事情在尊重地抬头
to being able to actually implement this in practice.
以便能够在实践中实际实现这一目标。
I want to talk about complexity.
我想谈谈复杂性。
And I promise that there was a subtlety associated
我保证会有一个微妙的关联
with the complexity of division in relation to multiplication,
由于除法与乘法有关的复杂性，
but let me just go over and write down what I just told you
但让我走过去写下我刚才告诉你的内容
with respect to the number of iterations
关于迭代次数
that division requires.
该师要求。
So division, quadratic convergence.
如此划分，二次收敛。
So number of digits doubles at each step.
因此，每一步的位数都会翻倍。
Good news.
好消息。
So d digits of precision, log d iterations.
因此，精度为d位，记录d次迭代。
Now let's say that we have a particular algorithm
现在说我们有一个特定的算法
for multiplication that I'm just going to say,
我要说的是乘法
since we have so many different algorithms,
由于我们有很多不同的算法，
I'm going to say multiplication in theta n raised
我要说的是乘法
to alpha time, where alpha is greater than or equal to 1.
到alpha时间，其中alpha大于或等于1。
I just want to be general about it.
我只是想对此有所概括。
And so assuming that I have a multiplication algorithm, that
因此，假设我有一个乘法算法，
can run in theta n raised to alpha,
可以在theta n中升至alpha，
where clearly you know alpha can be 1.46 for Toom 3, et cetera.
很明显，您知道Toom 3等的alpha可以为1.46。
And it's not quite that for Schonhage-Strassen,
对于Schonhage-Strassen而言，这还不完全是，
but I just want to be working with one particular complexity.
但是我只想处理一种特殊的复杂性。
So I'll parameterize it in this fashion.
因此，我将以这种方式对其进行参数化。
And everything I say is going to be true for Schonhage-Strassen
我所说的一切对于Schonhage-Strassen都是正确的
and Furer as well.
还有Furer。
But first, easy question.
但是首先，一个简单的问题。
What is the complexity of division
分割的复杂性是什么
using the analysis that I've put on the board so far?
使用到目前为止我所做的分析？
n digit numbers it's going to be?
n位数字会是什么？
I wanna hear from you.
我想听听你的消息。
How many hard multipliers do I have?
我有几个硬乘法器？
Log of?
的记录？
AUDIENCE: n.
听众：
PROFESSOR: Log of n, right?
教授：n的对数，对不对？
It wasn't a hard question.
这不是一个难题。
So division would be theta log n times n raised to alpha.
因此除法将是theta log n乘以n升至alpha。
Everybody buy that?
大家都买吗？
No?
没有？
Ask a question if you're confused.
问一个问题，如果您感到困惑。
Maybe I should say everybody buy that?
也许我应该说每个人都买那个？
How many people agree with that?
有多少人同意？
Big O?
大O？
How many people agree with that?
有多少人同意？
Yeah, that's right.
是啊，没错。
Big O. I'm hedging my bets here.
大O。我在这里对冲我的赌注。
I'm just saying big O. I could say big O of n cubed
我只是说大O。我可以说n的大O
and you should all agree with me.
你们都应该同意我的看法。
Or big O of whatever.
还是大O
You had a question?
你有问题吗
AUDIENCE: What's the longest [INAUDIBLE]
听众：最长的[听不清]
number of [INAUDIBLE] we need to get
我们需要获得的[音频不清晰]数量
a certain level of [INAUDIBLE]?
一定水平的[听不清]？
PROFESSOR: That's right.
教授：是的。
So if you want d digits of precision,
因此，如果您想要d位精度，
then according to this argument-- and I think you
然后根据这个论点-我想你
guys are a little doubtful here because I
大家在这里有点怀疑，因为我
kept talking about subtleties, and in fact there's
一直在谈论微妙之处，实际上
a subtlety here, which I want to get to-- but this big O
这是我想讲的一个微妙之处-但是这个大O
thing is perfectly correct.
事情是完全正确的。
But to answer your question, yes.
但是要回答你的问题，是的。
Let's assume that it's n digits of precision.
假设它是n位精度。
That's what we assume whether it's n or d.
这就是我们假设它是n还是d。
You can plug in the appropriate symbol here.
您可以在此处插入适当的符号。
And we're saying that, look, every iteration is bounded
而且，我们说的是，每次迭代都是有界的
by n raised to alpha complexity for the multiply.
乘以n会增加乘法的alpha复杂度。
And I'm going to do a logarithmic number
我要做一个对数
of iterations.
的迭代。
So I end up getting log n times n raised to alpha.
因此，我最终得到n乘以n的对数到alpha。
So that is correct, in fact.
因此，这是正确的。
Big O is correct.
大O是正确的。
So now it comes to the interesting question,
所以现在谈到一个有趣的问题，
which is can you do a better analysis?
您可以对哪个进行更好的分析？
So this sort of hearkens back to three weeks
所以这种听觉可以追溯到三个星期
ago, maybe you've forgotten.
以前，也许你已经忘记了。
Maybe you've blanked it out of your memory,
也许您已经把它清空了，
but I thought I described to you build max-heap.
但我以为我向您描述了如何建立最大堆。
And we had this straightforward analysis
我们进行了直接分析
of build max-heap that was n log n complexity.
构建最大堆的复杂度为n log n。
And then we looked at it a little more carefully,
然后我们更仔细地看了看它，
and we started adding things up much more carefully.
并且我们开始更加仔细地添加内容。
We turned into bank accountants.
我们变成了银行会计师。
And then we decided that it was theta n complexity.
然后我们认为这是复杂性。
People remember that?
人们还记得吗？
Right?
对？
So I want you to turn into bank accountants
所以我要你变成银行会计
again, and then tell me first, there's a nice observation
再次，然后先告诉我，有一个很好的观察
that you can make here that we haven't made yet
你可以在这里做我们还没有做的
with respect to the size of these numbers.
关于这些数字的大小。
We know what we want to eventually,
我们知道我们最终想要的是什么，
but there's a nice observation we can make it with respect
但有一个很好的观察，我们可以尊重
to the size of these numbers.
这些数字的大小。
And then we want to exploit that observation
然后我们要利用这一观察
to do a better analysis of the theta complexity of division.
以便更好地分析除法theta的复杂度。
So who wants to tell me what the observation is.
那么谁想告诉我观察是什么。
This is definitely worth a cushion.
这绝对值得缓冲。
What's the observation?
有什么发现？
I want to end up with d digits of precision.
我想以d位精度结束。
If I give you another hint, I'm gonna give it away.
如果我再给您一个提示，我就把它给您。
Someone tell me.
有人告诉我。
This is a dynamic process, OK?
这是一个动态的过程，好吗？
So what do I start with?
那么我从什么开始呢？
What do I start with?
我从什么开始？
If I want to compute something and you
如果我想计算一些东西，你
want to use Newton's method, what do you start with?
想要使用牛顿法，首先要做什么？
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: You start with one digit of precision.
教授：您以一位精度开始。
That's fantastic.
这太妙了。
I don't know if you already have a cushion or not,
我不知道你是否已经有了垫子
but here's the second one.
但是这是第二个。
So you start with a small number of digits of precision.
因此，您从少量的精度开始。
And then you end up with a large million, whatever, number,
然后您最终得到了不计其数的一百万，
which is your d.
这是你的d。
So what does that mean?
那是什么意思呢？
So now somebody take that and run with it.
所以现在有人接受它并运行它。
Somebody take that and run with it.
有人接受它并运行它。
You already have a cushion.
您已经有了坐垫。
Like many?
喜欢很多？
You guys, usual suspects.
你们，通常是嫌疑犯。
So someone take that and run with it.
所以有人接受它并运行它。
What can I do now?
我现在能做什么？
What does it mean if I start with a small number of digits
如果我以少量数字开头是什么意思
of precision?
精度？
My initial guess was one, right?
我最初的猜测是，对吧？
I mean, that had one digit of precision.
我的意思是，它的精度为一位数。
And then the number of digits doubles with each step.
然后，位数每增加一倍。
So is there any reason why I'm doing,
那我为什么要这么做
if I had d digits of precision, eventually
如果我有d位数的精度，最终
that I'll have to do d digit multiplies in each iteration?
我必须在每次迭代中做d位数乘法？
Any reason why?
有什么原因吗？
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: You don't have to, because [INAUDIBLE] multiplies
听众：您不必这样做，因为[听不清]会成倍增加
are going to be trivial.
将变得微不足道。
And [INAUDIBLE] then you're going to eventually approach
然后[听不清]，您将最终走近
the d to the alpha iteration.
d到alpha迭代。
PROFESSOR: That's exactly right.
教授：完全正确。
Exactly right.
非常正确。
That's worth a cushion.
值得缓冲。
But now I want you or someone else,
但是现在我要你或其他人，
tell me what the iteration looks like.
告诉我迭代的样子。
So this is the key observation.
因此，这是关键观察。
The key observation is that if I want d digits of precision,
关键的观察结果是，如果我想要d位精度，
I'm going to start with maybe one digit of precision.
我将从一位数的精度开始。
So this is d of p, or dig of p, not to be confused.
因此，不要混淆这是p的d或p的挖掘。
I start with 1, 2, 4, and I end up with d.
我从1、2、4开始，最后到d。
And our claim was that this was log d iterations, right?
我们声称这是对数d迭代，对吗？
So the initial multiplies are easy.
因此，初始乘法很容易。
Initially you're doing constant work
最初，您正在不断地工作
if you have really small numbers associated
如果您的数字很小
with these multiplies.
与这些相乘。
It's only towards the end that you end up
直到最后，你最终
doing a lot more work, right?
做更多的工作，对吗？
So someone tell me if I have n raised to alpha,
所以有人告诉我，如果我没有升到Alpha，
and if I say I want to write an equation.
如果我说我想写一个方程式。
And I don't want to use theta here.
我不想在这里使用theta。
I'm going to use constants because I
我将使用常量，因为我
want to add up constants, and it's a little iffy then
想加常数，这有点不确定
you add up thetas.
您将thetas加起来。
You need to be looking at constants.
您需要查看常量。
Now I can imagine that for this iteration, the very first one,
现在我可以想象到，对于这个迭代，第一个迭代，
that I have something like c times 1 raised to alpha,
我有c乘以1等于alpha的东西，
because it's just a single digit of precision.
因为这只是个位数的精度。
OK And the next one, I'm using the same algorithm.
好，下一个，我使用的是相同的算法。
This is c times 2 raised to alpha, c times 4
这是c乘2升至alpha的原因，c乘4
raised to alpha.
提高到Alpha。
And then out here I'm going to have
然后在这里我要
c times d by 4 raised to alpha plus c times d by 2
将c倍d乘以4升至alpha加c倍d乘2
raised to alpha plus finally c times d raised to alpha.
加至alpha，最后加c倍d加至alpha。
And someone give me a bound.
有人给我束缚。
Who wants to give me a bound on this?
谁想在这方面给我一个约束？
Less than or equal to.
小于或等于。
Let's just make it less than.
让我们使其小于。
What?
什么？
Someone?
有人吗
Just plug in a value of alpha.
只需插入一个alpha值即可。
And remember your convergent geometric series and things
并记住您收敛的几何级数和事物
like that.
像那样。
What is that?
那是什么？
Someone?
有人吗
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: Just some constant times d to the alpha?
听众：只是相对于alpha的恒定时间d？
PROFESSOR: That's exactly right.
教授：完全正确。
Just some constant times d to the alpha.
只是一些恒定时间d到alpha。
And in fact, you can say, it's 2c d to the alpha.
实际上，您可以说，它是alpha的2c d。
Keep a question for you aside.
将问题抛在一边。
So that' sit.
就是这样了。
That's the little careful analysis that we had to do,
那是我们要做的一点细心的分析，
which basically without changing your code, really,
基本上，无需更改代码，
suddenly gave you a better complexity.
突然给您带来了更好的复杂性。
Isn't that fun?
那不是很有趣吗？
That's always fun.
总是很有趣。
You had this neat algorithm to begin with.
您首先需要使用这种整洁的算法。
And bottom line is you're just computing things
最重要的是，您只是在计算事物
a little more accurately, than essentially saying
比本质上说的要准确一点
that you had to do all of this work
你必须做所有这些工作
with large number of digits of precision at every iteration.
每次迭代都具有大量的精度。
The number of digits actually increases.
位数实际上增加了。
So what does this mean?
那么这是什么意思？
I guess ultimately, the complexity of division
我想最终是分裂的复杂性
is now what?
现在是什么？
It's the same as the complexity of multiplication, right?
和乘法的复杂度一样，对吗？
So regardless of whether we did a Newton iteration or not,
因此，无论我们是否进行牛顿迭代，
the complexity of division.
划分的复杂性。
You are doing a logarithmic number of iterations,
您正在做对数迭代，
but since eventually all of the work
但由于最终所有工作
is going to get done at the end here.
将在这里结束。
Most of the work is getting done at the end when
大部分工作在最后完成时
you have these long numbers.
你有这么长的数字。
That's basically the essence of the argument.
这基本上是论点的本质。
So let me finish up and talk about the complexity
所以让我结束并谈论复杂性
of computing square roots.
计算平方根。
And as you can imagine, even though you
可以想像，即使您
have two nested Newton iterations here,
这里有两个嵌套的牛顿迭代，
you can make basically the same argument.
您可以提出基本相同的论点。
So let's recall what we're doing in terms
让我们回想一下我们在做的事情
of computing square roots.
计算平方根。
We want to compute square root of a.
我们要计算a的平方根。
And we said, well we don't quite know how to do this.
我们说过，嗯，我们不太了解如何做到这一点。
We're going to end up doing 10 raised to 2d times a,
我们最终要把10次提高到2d次，
and we're going to run Newton's method on it.
我们将在其上运行牛顿方法。
So you've got one level of Newton's method.
因此，您已经有了牛顿方法的一个层次。
And the iteration here with respect to Newton's method
还有关于牛顿法的迭代
is something like xi plus 1 equals xi plus a divided by xi.
是xi加1等于xi加除以xi的东西。
Now every time you do that for a particular xi,
现在，每次针对特定xi进行此操作时，
you're going to end up having to call a division.
您最终将不得不致电部门。
So you're going to call a division here,
所以你要在这里打电话给一个部门，
and then you're going to call a division here.
然后您将在这里致电部门。
For each iteration you have to call a division.
对于每次迭代，您都必须调用一个除法。
And what we're saying is, well we're
我们的意思是，
going to end up having to call for each of these division
最终不得不呼吁每个部门
methods we're going to call Newton's method.
方法我们将调用牛顿方法。
And what that is something like 2xi
那就像2xi
minus b xi square divided by r.
减去b xi平方除以r。
And that's going to be a bunch of multiplications.
这将是一堆乘法。
And what we argued up until this point was
到目前为止，我们争论的是
that the complexity of the division,
划分的复杂性，
even though we had a bunch of iterations here,
即使我们在这里有很多迭代，
a logarithmic number of iterations, the complexity
对数迭代，复杂度
of the division was the same as the complexity
的划分与复杂度相同
of the multiplication because the numbers
的乘法，因为数字
started out small and grew big.
从小到大开始。
All right?
好吧？
Everybody buy that?
大家都买吗？
I'm going to use exactly the same argument
我将使用完全相同的参数
for this level of iteration as well.
对于此迭代级别也是如此。
And again, when you start out with the digits of precision
再说一遍，当您以精确度开始
corresponding to square root of 2,
对应于2的平方根
you're going to start out guessing 1.5,
您将开始猜测1.5，
which is your initial guess for the square root of 2,
这是您对2的平方根的初始猜测
and it's going to be a small number of digits of precision.
它将是少量的精度。
And eventually you'll get to a million digits.
最终您将获得一百万个数字。
So using essentially the same equation summing,
因此，使用基本相同的方程求和
you can argue that the complexity of computing
你可以说计算的复杂性
square roots is the complexity of division, which of course is
平方根是分割的复杂性，这当然是
the complexity of multiplication.
乘法的复杂性。
And that's the story.
这就是故事。
So obviously the code would be a little more complicated
所以很明显，代码会更加复杂
than a multiplication code, because you
而不是乘法代码，因为您
have all this control structure outside of it.
拥有所有这些控制结构。
It's really two nested loops.
这实际上是两个嵌套循环。
The multiply is getting called a bunch of times
乘数被称为一堆倍
to do the divide, and the divide is
进行除法，而除法是
getting called a bunch of times to compute the square root.
被多次调用以计算平方根。
But ultimately, because the numbers are growing
但最终，因为数字在增长
and you start out with small numbers, most of the work
然后您从少量开始，大部分工作
is done when you get to the millions of digits
当您获得数百万个数字时就完成了
of precision.
的精度。
And you basically have theta n raised
你基本上提出了
to alpha complexity for computing square roots.
到计算平方根的alpha复杂度。
If you have n raised to alpha multiply,
如果您将n提高到alpha乘，
and you want n digits of precision.
而您想要n位精度。
All right?
好吧？
See you next time.
下次见。
Stick around for questions.
坚持问问题。